=Yes, Her Majesty=
= نعم صاحبة الجلالة =
=Episode 6=
= الحلقة 6 =
(Imperial study)
(دراسة إمبراطورية)
Li Xiao is here to greet Your Majesty.
لي شياو هنا لتحية جلالة الملك.
General Li, please rise.
الجنرال لي ، الرجاء النهوض.
(Why do I feel like I'm close to General Li?)
(لماذا أشعر أنني قريب من الجنرال لي؟)
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
General Li.
الجنرال لي.
The Empress has told me about
أخبرتني الإمبراطورة عن
how I'm replacing the Crown Prince.
كيف سأحل محل ولي العهد.
General Li, you're the pillar of the nation.
الجنرال لي ، أنت عمود الأمة.
I hereby thank you for that.
بموجب هذا أشكرك على ذلك.
Your Majesty, don't say that.
جلالة الملك ، لا تقل ذلك.
Being loyal and serving the nation is my duty.
من واجبي أن أكون مخلصًا وخدمة الوطن.
The imperial court is not stable yet.
البلاط الإمبراطوري غير مستقر بعد.
I'll be more diligent and careful.
سأكون أكثر اجتهادًا وحذرًا.
I hope you'll assist me.
أتمنى أن تساعدني.
Your Majesty has that realisation,
جلالة الملك لديه هذا الإدراك ،
it's a blessing to the nation.
إنها نعمة للأمة.
I'll do my best.
سافعل ما بوسعي.
Your Majesty, your real birthday is coming soon,
جلالة الملك ، عيد ميلادك الحقيقي سيأتي قريبًا ،
but we can't celebrate openly.
لكن لا يمكننا الاحتفال علانية.
My wife has made some Jiangnan snacks for your birthday celebration.
أعدت زوجتي بعض الوجبات الخفيفة في جيانغنان للاحتفال بعيد ميلادك.
That's so kind of you.
هذا لطفا منك.
I've almost forgotten about Her Majesty's real birthday.
كدت أنسى عيد ميلاد جلالة الملكة الحقيقي.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
This is the most trendy lipstick.
هذا هو أحمر الشفاه الأكثر رواجًا.
It's good, moisturising, and won't make our lips dry.
إنه جيد ومرطب ولن يجعل شفاهنا جافة.
It can fulfill our everyday needs.
يمكن أن تلبي احتياجاتنا اليومية.
Your Highness, this is foreign sea pearl.
صاحب السمو ، هذه لؤلؤة البحر الأجنبية.
Every man can only customise once in his lifetime.
يمكن لكل رجل التخصيص مرة واحدة فقط في حياته.
What about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
I bought one and got one free.
اشتريت واحدة وحصلت على واحدة مجانا.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Look at this.
انظر إلى هذا.
This is the scarce morelia viridis leather bag.
هذه هي الحقيبة الجلدية النادرة من Morelia viridis.
The skin is rare.
الجلد نادر.
It's exclusive in Great Yan.
إنه حصري في Great Yan.
Put it down.
ضعه أرضا، أنزله.
How can your taste be so bad?
كيف يمكن أن يكون ذوقك سيئًا للغاية؟
This is my birthday gift to Her Majesty.
هذه هدية عيد ميلادي لصاحبة الجلالة.
How can it be these lousy goods?
كيف يمكن أن تكون هذه البضائع الرديئة؟
It's such an important event.
إنه حدث مهم.
Can't you all be more serious?
ألا يمكن أن تكونوا جميعًا أكثر جدية؟
Whether I can...
ما إذا كان بإمكاني ...
Whether I can give birth to a prince with Her Majesty or not
ما إذا كان بإمكاني أن أنجب أميرًا مع صاحبة الجلالة أم لا
depends on
يعتمد على
this birthday gift.
هدية عيد الميلاد هذه.
Your Highness, what gift do you think
سموك ، ما هي الهدية التي تعتقدها
is not lousy?
ليس رديئا؟
Empress...
الإمبراطورة ...
Close your eyes.
اغلق عينيك.
Listen.
يستمع.
The bug's chirping is loud.
نقيق الحشرة بصوت عال.
♪A flower blooms before the rain falls♪
♪ زهرة تتفتح قبل سقوط المطر ♪
♪A moon could be full or in half♪
♪ يمكن أن يكون القمر كاملاً أو نصفه ♪
♪How does a worm transform into a butterfly?♪
♪ كيف تتحول الدودة إلى فراشة؟
♪A handful of snow illuminates your eyelashes♪
♪ حفنة من الثلج تضيء رموشك
♪Riding the wind to the boundaries of your heart♪
ركوب الريح إلى حدود قلبك ♪
♪Gazing at the vast wilderness while riding a horse under the moon♪
التحديق في البرية الشاسعة أثناء ركوب الخيل تحت القمر ♪
♪You couldn't reach the entire dream♪
♪ لا يمكنك الوصول إلى الحلم كله
♪I freeze the pages of time flipping through them♪
♪ أقوم بتجميد صفحات الوقت أثناء تقليبها ♪
♪Stopping at the four seasons of you and me♪
التوقف عند الفصول الأربعة بيني وبينك
♪Stopping at the whispering in your ear and at the parting♪
التوقف عند الهمس في أذنك وعند الفراق ♪
♪Stopping at the other side going through the mountains and rivers♪
التوقف عند الجانب الآخر مروراً بالجبال والأنهار
♪Stopping at this moment where you are the whole world♪
♪ توقف في هذه اللحظة حيث أنت العالم كله
Spring flower.
زهرة الربيع.
Autumn moon.
قمر الخريف.
Summer bugs.
حشرات الصيف.
Winter snow.
ثلج الشتاء.
Your Majesty, the natural scenery is beautiful in all four seasons.
جلالة الملك ، المناظر الطبيعية جميلة في جميع الفصول الأربعة.
How many people in the world are truly at leisure?
كم عدد الأشخاص في العالم الذين يقضون أوقات فراغهم حقًا؟
This is the first birthday gift
هذه أول هدية عيد ميلاد
I've prepared for Your Majesty.
لقد أعددت لجلالتك.
Great four seasons.
أربعة مواسم رائعة.
Great four seasons?
أربعة مواسم رائعة؟
You've once told me that
لقد أخبرتني بذلك مرة واحدة
you're always trapped in the palace.
كنت دائما محاصرا في القصر.
You haven't seen any four seasons.
أنت لم ترى أي أربعة مواسم.
So,
لذا،
I've brought four seasons to see you.
لقد أحضرت أربعة مواسم لرؤيتك.
♪Stopping at the beginning of the story and at the innocence♪
التوقف عند بداية القصة وعند البراءة
♪Stopping at the end of the story for our temples turning white with snow♪
♪ التوقف في نهاية القصة عن معابدنا تتحول إلى اللون الأبيض بالثلج
♪Stopping in the pages of history described in just a few lines♪
التوقف في صفحات التاريخ الموصوفة في بضعة أسطر ♪
Happy birthday,
عيد ميلاد سعيد،
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
♪Flowers and leaves♪
الزهور والأوراق ♪
Come with me.
تعال معي.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
this is the second gift I've prepared for your birthday.
هذه هي الهدية الثانية التي أعددتها لعيد ميلادك.
Do you like it?
هل أحببت ذلك؟
What is this?
ما هذا؟
This is a cake.
هذه كعكة.
It's made of Jinling rice and Nantian flour.
إنه مصنوع من أرز جينلينج ودقيق نانتيان.
It means breaking of a new day.
إنه يعني كسر يوم جديد.
I used up a whole day to make this.
لقد استهلكت يومًا كاملاً لعمل هذا.
It's tough.
انها صعبة أوخشنة
What about this fat doll?
ماذا عن هذه الدمية السمينة؟
It's the sugar dough doll that I made.
إنها دمية عجين السكر التي صنعتها.
Your Majesty, don't you think she looks like...
جلالة الملك ، ألا تعتقد أنها تشبه ...
May Great Yan be prosperous!
أتمنى أن تكون يان العظيمة مزدهرة!
Empress, this is auspicious.
إمبراطورة ، هذا ميمون.
Here.
هنا.
Look here. The rice, the shell
انظر هنا.  الأرز ، القشرة
and the Doll of Prosperity.
ودمية الرخاء.
Doll of Prosperity?
دمية الرخاء؟
Look at the doll.
انظر إلى الدمية.
She's short and fat. That's a blessing.
إنها قصيرة وبدينة.  هذه نعمة.
Isn't she the God of Prosperity?
أليست هي إله الرخاء؟
Yes.
نعم.
She's the God of Prosperity.
إنها إله الرخاء.
If Her Majesty found out that this is her,
إذا علمت جلالة الملكة أن هذه هي ،
she might vomit blood.
قد تتقيأ دما.
My jinxed mouth was not working on him.
لم يكن فمي النحس يعمل عليه.
Let me try again.
دعني احاول مجددا.
Blow the flour onto his face.
انفخ الدقيق في وجهه.
Three, two, one, blow.
ثلاثة ، اثنان ، واحد ، ضربة.
Are you okay?
هل أنت بخير؟
I'm okay!
أنا بخير!
His Highness and I were making cakes.
سموه وأنا كنا نصنع الكعك.
I made one too.
لقد صنعت واحدة أيضًا.
See if it looks like you.
انظر إذا كان يشبهك.
It does look like me.
انها تبدو مثلي
It's quite tasty too.
إنه لذيذ جدًا أيضًا.
Do you want to try?
هل ترغب بالمحاولة؟
You can eat it all.
يمكنك أن تأكلها كلها.
Wait.
انتظر.
How does it taste?
كيف طعمها؟
Is it nice?
هل هذا حلو؟
It's not too bad.
انها ليست سيئة للغاية.
Wait.
انتظر.
What rice did you use to make this?
ما الأرز الذي استخدمته لصنع هذا؟
Jinling rice.
أرز جينلينج.
There's something wrong with the rice.
هناك شيء خاطئ في الأرز.
Your Majesty, this is not Jinling rice.
جلالة الملك ، هذا ليس أرز جينلينج.
This is only the normal fragrant rice.
هذا هو الأرز الطبيعي المعطر فقط.
Are you sure?
هل أنت متأكد؟
The tribute item for the imperial palace is Jinling rice.
عنصر الجزية للقصر الإمبراطوري هو أرز جينلينغ.
Jinling rice and fragrant rice's texture is similar.
قوام الأرز جينلينج والأرز المعطر متشابه.
But Jinling rice
لكن أرز جينلينج
has the special fragrance of honeysuckle flower in Jinling.
له رائحة خاصة من زهرة زهر العسل في جينلينغ.
I grew up in Jinling.
لقد نشأت في جينلينغ.
I came into the palace at 16.
جئت إلى القصر في السادسة عشرة.
I'll never recognise it wrongly.
لن أتعرف عليه بشكل خاطئ أبدًا.
Yes.
نعم.
It's the smell of honeysuckle flower.
إنها رائحة زهرة زهر العسل.
This is weird.
هذا غريب.
Have I been to Jinling?
هل زرت جينلينج؟
Why is the taste so familiar...
لماذا الطعم مألوف جدا ...
Your Majesty's favourite was Jinling rice before you were drowned.
مفضل جلالة الملك كان أرز جينلينج قبل أن تغرق.
Right, Lan Ruo?
حق لان رو؟
Yes.
نعم.
Your Majesty used to eat Jinling rice every day.
صاحب الجلالة كان يأكل أرز جينلينج كل يوم.
Your Majesty, the most urgent matter
جلالة الملك ، الأمر الأكثر إلحاحًا
is to find out the truth of Jinling rice being swapped.
هو معرفة حقيقة تبادل أرز جينلينج.
How could someone use fragrant rice to replace Jinling rice?
كيف يمكن لشخص ما أن يستخدم الأرز المعطر ليحل محل أرز جينلينج؟
It's too daring.
إنه جريء للغاية.
Kong Gu, you'll be in charge of this matter.
كونغ جو ، ستكون مسؤولاً عن هذا الأمر.
You must investigate thoroughly.
يجب عليك التحقيق بدقة.
Yes.
نعم.
Your Majesty, swapping the tribute rice is a serious matter.
جلالة الملك ، مبادلة أرز الجزية أمر خطير.
Many people will be involved.
سيشارك الكثير من الناس.
I think we should act quietly.
أعتقد أننا يجب أن نتصرف بهدوء.
Empress, do you have any idea?
إمبراطورة ، هل لديك أي فكرة؟
♪Even though it's hard to say goodbye♪
♪ رغم أنه من الصعب أن نقول وداعًا
♪We're nothing compared to the world♪
♪ نحن لا شيء مقارنة بالعالم ♪
♪Holding deep grudges♪
يحمل ضغائن عميقة ♪
♪But flowers blossom late♪
♪ لكن الزهور تتفتح متأخرة ♪
♪Asking why we need to be apart♪
يسأل لماذا يجب أن نفترق ♪
♪Waiting from new moon to full moon♪
♪ الانتظار من القمر الجديد إلى اكتمال القمر
♪Vow becomes poem♪
نذر يصبح قصيدة ♪
♪But I dare not read it♪
♪ لكنني لا أجرؤ على قراءتها ♪
♪Even though it's hard to say goodbye♪
♪ رغم أنه من الصعب أن نقول وداعًا
♪We're nothing compared to the world♪
♪ نحن لا شيء مقارنة بالعالم ♪
♪Holding deep grudges♪
يحمل ضغائن عميقة ♪
♪But flowers blossom late♪
♪ لكن الزهور تتفتح متأخرة ♪